The University of Arizona and World War II, 1942-1951
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
The University of Arizona and World War II, 1942-1951
AZ 025
Cosulich, Bernice,1896-1956.
Reports,faculty and staff questionnaires, and other material gathered by the University for use in the creation of this manuscript which documented the UA's involvement in World War II.
O.4 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on this collection
Biographical Note
Bernice Cosulich was born in Iowa in 1896. She married Gilbert Cosulich in 1916 and they had one daughter, Donna. Together they lived on the southern border of the United States and in Mexico City. Ms. Cosulich moved to Tucson and reported for the Arizona Daily Star from 1922-1948 as the “state’s best known newspaperwoman.” Her best work was on the Colorado River Controversy. She simultaneously worked as a correspondent for the New York Times, Life, Time and Fortune. She covered the Arizona state legislature from 1941-1946. Cosulich retired in 1948 due to health reasons, but continued to research and published a book in 1953 called Tucson.
Arrangement
This publication is arranged by the type of material
Scope and Content Note
Original typescript, with reports, faculty and staff questionnaires, and other material gathered by the University during 1942-1945 and used in preparation of this manuscript. Includes a lists of students and faculty who served in the war along with their rank, branch of service, school, and year of graduation; list of those who died in the war; and a separate list of women who served.
Cosulich, Bernice,1896-1956; World War, 1939-1945--Arizona; University of Arizona--History
Container List
- The University of Arizona and World Ward II, manuscript, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous material, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Reports (general), undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Reports of deans, departments, etc., 1942 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Department heads questionnaire, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Department heads questionnaire, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Faculty questionnaire, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Faculty and staff questionnaire, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Senior questionnaire, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Students and faculty in the Armed Forces, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)